opticalexpress.nl 2019-05-24

# Privacy Policy - Optical Express

Optical Express is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy, being transparent about the personal information we hold and giving you control over how it is used. This Privacy Policy sets out the type of personal information we collect about you, why we collect it and how we use it. It also provides you with information about your rights and who to contact if you have any questions or queries. Your trust is important to us.

Please read the following carefully and contact our Data Protection Officer below, if you have any queries about our privacy practices or policy.

We may update our privacy policy in the future and it is important that you check it from time to time. If we make changes we think are important, we will inform you by placing a notice on the relevant service/website and/or contact you by other methods of communication, such as email.

### How do we collect your personal information?

We collect personal information from you:

  * When you fill in forms on our website www.opticalexpress.co.uk This includes at the time of registering to use our website, subscribing to our service, posting material or requesting further services including when you request a call back and booking an appointment, and when you enter a competition or promotion sponsored by Optical Express, or when applying for a career with Optical Express.

  * When you visit our website (including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise) and the resources that you access. You can find out more about the cookies we use in the section below.

  * When you report a problem with our website.

  * When you fill in electronic or hard copy documents or forms in our clinics and stores associated with the performing of any form of ophthalmic examination, such as an eye examination (sight test), a contact lens related consultation, a pre-operative consultation to assess suitability of surgery, to conduct a surgical procedure or in the provision of any post-operative care.

  * By completing feedback surveys/forms.

  * Should you make a complaint, either verbally or by another form of communication such as letter or email.

  * Through transactions (complete and incomplete orders) you carry out through any medium, such as on our website, in a clinic or store and by telephone.

  * Via telephone calls with you.

  * Via CCTV operating at our premise.

_We may record telephone calls with you in order to check facts, for ensuring compliance with regulatory practices and improving the quality of our customer service._

We also collect your personal information from different sources:

  * From social media.

  * Via third parties such as external medical professionals (to include your General Practitioner or another Opticians practice), hospitals, and your family members.

  * Companies that provide consumer classification for marketing purposes.

### Your rights

Data Protection law provides you with rights to the personal information we hold about you. These rights are:

**The right to access your personal information**

You are entitled to access your personal information we hold. This means you can request a copy of the personal information held by us. There is not usually a charge for dealing with your request. For any additional copies however we will charge a reasonable fee for administrative costs. We will usually provide your information in writing, unless otherwise requested, or where you have made the request electronically we will strive to provide you with your data by electronic means where possible.

**The right to withdraw consent**

We will ask for your consent for certain uses of your personal information notably marketing. You can ask us to stop sending you marketing at any time.

Where you have consented we will provide you with information, products or services from the Optical Express group of companies that we feel may interest you. Each of these communications clearly carries an unsubscribe option in the event that such information is not welcomed.

**The right to rectification**

We strive to keep your personal information accurate and complete. However if you do believe this is not the case you can ask us to update or amend it. Details on how to contact us are provided in this privacy policy.

**The right to erasure**

In certain circumstances you have the right to ask us to erase your personal information, for example when the personal information is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was collected or where you have withdrawn your consent. However we may not fulfil such a request if there are legal or regulatory obligations that mean we cannot erase your personal information or where it is necessary to continue eye care services or treatment.

**The right to restriction of processing**

In certain circumstances you have the right to ask us to stop using your personal information, for example where you believe the information we hold about you is inaccurate. However we may not fulfil such a request if there are legal or regulatory obligations that means we cannot do so or where it is necessary to continue eye care services or treatment.

**The right to data portability**

In certain circumstances you have the right to ask us to transfer personal information, that you have provided to us, to another third party where this is technically feasible. Once your personal information has been transferred to a third party, of your choice, they are responsible for safeguarding your personal information.

**The right to lodge a complaint**

You have a right to make a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) at any time in circumstances where consider your personal information has been used by us in a way that does not comply with data protection law. More information is available on the [ICO website: ico.org.uk/concerns/](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/)

### Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and our Data Protection Officer can be contacted by writing to:

Address: Optical Express, 200 St Vincent Street, Glasgow, G2 5RQ

Email: [DPO@opticalexpress.com](mailto:DPO@opticalexpress.com)

If you would like to contact the UK’s Information Commissioner’s Officer direct write to:  
Address: the Information Commissioner's Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AF.  
Telephone: 0303 123 1113 (local rate) or 01625 545 745 if you prefer to use a national rate number. [ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/](https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/)

### Optical Express Company Details

Optical Express Limited SC161469 – Incorporated on 3 November 1995   
The Ca'D'Oro, 45 Gordon Street, Glasgow, G1 3PE

Optical Express (Westfield) Ltd SC161695 - Incorporated on 17 November 1995   
The Ca'D'Oro, 45 Gordon Street Glasgow, G1 3PE

Optical Express (Gyle) Ltd SC150432 - Incorporated on 22 April 1994   
The Ca'D'Oro, 45 Gordon Street, Glasgow, G1 3PE

The Frame Zone Ltd SC182069 Incorporated on 13 January 1998   
The Ca'D'Oro, 45 Gordon Street, Glasgow, G1 3PE
